Clock just
signaled 07:00,
so it is time to call to order this regular meeting
of the Andover,
Hidden, Wildlands, and Water Corridors' Commission,
06/05/2023,
seven p. M.
I see that we have on the call
Commissioner Larson,
Commissioner Monroe, Commissioner Fife,
Commissioner Mashke indicated
she might be late joining the meeting, so we'll see if she can show up.
Are there any suggestions
for a change to the order or additions to the agenda?
Okay,
seeing none, we'll move to item number four of the agenda,
approval of the minutes from March 6. It's been a while, obviously, since that meeting.
I'm looking at a document
labeled,
let me see what the title is,
3.6.2023
IWWC
Meeting, Motions, Minutes, Andover Regular,
and
I hope that we're all on the same page with that.
I'll give you a minute to peruse,
and
then I'll entertain a motion to approve
the minutes
and or any amendments thereto.
So, any questions or comments regarding the minutes?
Okay,
then
motion to
approve those minutes and a second.
I'll make a motion to approve.
>> Yes, I move. And a second,
Commissioner Munroe.
Without amendments,
we can proceed to a vote
by
roll call in order of alphabet
by Commissioner Larson.
Aye.
>> Commissioner Munro.
Aye. Commissioner Fife.
Are you on?
Mr. Fife, you have one. There you go.
And I also vote aye, so the motion carries 400.
I don't see any public to comment,
and we don't have any old business to consider,
neither do we have any new applications or business of which to take receipt.
There are several
agent
action enforcement
actions,
which I will turn over to
Agent Wagner to describe and discuss.
>> That's been been a while since our last meeting, so I kinda been slow, but I have had a few things.
The most recent was the
'23 dash o five, which was the construction of the community garden. So they cleared some trees,
put a bunch of fill in, leveled it off, and they're in the process of building some boxes over there. And then they also there was some
a pile of
topsoil that had been there from a previous construction,
maybe when they built the firehouse or town hall or something. I don't know. It's been there for a while, so they they ended up taking that.
I don't know if they use it at this project or they use it somewhere else, but they graded and seeded everything.
So it's pretty much
done now. Our
impact some of it was in the
Upland review area. Some of it wasn't. It was kinda on the edge.
Mhmm.
And then
we had 23
o four. That was the one I talked to you about a while back when
the Connecticut Meditation Center built a shelter
over their their statue, a wooden structure, the roof over their statue.
So they applied
for the permit.
It's pretty detailed application,
actually. And they
they said it was temporary. So eventually, I mean, they don't have anything in now. Eventually, they're planning on putting an actual building over there. So
there's definitely a lot of wetlands on that property. So that would would come before the commission when it happens if it does.
The other one was,
23 Dash 03 in April 12. That was 196
Lake Road.
The property owner wants to demolish his 20 by 21
car garage and build a two
car garage, 24 by 30 foot in the same location.
Say the plans, wasn't too much bigger,
and he's working with Jim to put
a drywall in to capture the
water that's coming off of the shed off of the garage, I mean.
Then we got March 13 was the
removal and reconstruction of a 80 foot by three foot masonry wall and a 52 by four foot masonry wall. They weren't on the lake. They're kinda, like, halfway up the yard. I forget exactly how far, but it was,
I don't know, probably 30 feet if I had to guess away from the lake 30 or 40 feet. So there was one and then there was another one, were kind of terrorist and they were starting to collapse.
So
they
they're getting those rebuilt or got them rebuilt. I'm not sure if they're finished yet.
Couple other things that I didn't put on the agenda was I met with
Ryan Fitch from Fitch Family Farm.
Met with him on the thirtieth,
and he was he's
still planning on cleaning up those trees in the pond. He's trying to hire a crew,
for his landscaping company,
and he's gonna
work with me when they get done. So that'll be
probably midsummer,
which I think would be better as far as a
vernal pool. We've well out of the vernal pool season.
Hopefully, it'd be a little drier there.
So it's still fun to get that done.
And then 88,
that one came in today. That's a new
new house,
and the house is outside of the Upland Review area.
But the footing there's a footing drain that goes, like, 40 feet in.
So I had to put a permit in for that.
It's just a simple project, but I just got that today. I'll post the materials on there on probably tomorrow.
Then I got 409 Lake Road.
I've been talking to them.
They're
post done, they put the electrical utilities
in next to the driveway. They've seeded it. They fixed some of the ruts that they put in the wetland area when they cleared it, and they're kinda haphazardly about that.
So they fixed that.
The driveway is pretty much done. They're gonna put another layer of gravel on it once they're further along in the process
of construction. I think that's, like, the final one of the final steps. But as far as excavating over there, I think they're they're pretty much done.
And then I'm gonna work with Judy about the wetlands plantings and stuff. She's gonna pull off on that till next year, I think.
And then you guys I said I emailed you guys a Algonquin pipeline maintenance notice
that I got last week that they're gonna do some work off of what was that? I
think
They found a couple one one thing they had to investigate, I guess.
And it's in
wetlands, but they we don't have a jurisdiction over that.
So
and that's all I got.
>> Okay.
Any
questions from the commission about
any of these
permits or enforcements?
>> I'd just like to thank Joe for
coordinating
with Jim on
the nutrient
allocation stuff. These
dry wells, well, guess 409 had a little, you know, they had the detention pond kind of thing, but those seem to be
going now as opposed to it got tough to get started initially,
but
you and Jim must have the trick because they seem to be working okay now. I appreciate
>> efforts on that. We're kinda figuring it out. It's it's
the way it works with wetlands and everything. We kinda have to work on it together anyway. So but, yeah, it's getting there.
>> Yeah. Much better than it was a year or so ago. Yeah.
>> Good. Yeah. Glad to hear that. And
again,
appreciate your
ability to stay on top of,
these projects and, keep us informed
of what's going on on the ground. You know, again, as Commissioner Larson pointed out many times,
issuing as a permit
is one thing,
seeing it through and actually realizing the conditions being met
can be quite another.
The Commission can look forward to more of that.
Okay, so
that
concludes
the agent report.
We can move on to our item other business, which is of course the perennial
issue of membership and recruitment,
this specifically
for the term
beginning 07/01/2023,
and ending 06/30/2025.
I did poll the membership
per request from Town Clerk Carol Lee and informed her of the results, which is as follows:
Continuing members will include
Commissioner Larson,
Commissioner Monroe, and Commissioner Fife as regular members.
Circumstances led
tooh, I see that Commissioner Mackay is just joining the call now,
and so I wanted to report that she
will continue but on an alternate basis.
Finally, Commissioner
Smith,
who's
not present for tonight's meeting and
been
willing to continue to serve as a
nominal alternate
in case we
need to make up a quorum,
has indicated that he will continue in that in hopes that
and anticipates that in January
his circumstances
will allow him to
step up to a regular membership
on the commission. He was a regular member at one point, and the other
activities
led him to,
as it were, drop back to alternate.
But as I say, he expressed
in anticipation
of being able to step up as a regular member.
I, on the other hand,
am not going to continue. I felt that one thing and another,
will
be
in the best interest of all of us if I don't continue on the commission. And I enjoyed
doing it, I feel that I'm still
competent. But
at
my age, you don't want to cut on and make things for too long.
So,
as I say, I'm resigning the Commission
effective at the end of this month. Now,
that gives me twenty five days
to finish up a little bit of work.
The
new chair will have to be elected in July per
commission
bylaws,
and
I hope that you all will have a more amicable time in
succession
than the recent HBO series.
I don't know if anybody watched that one, but it was a
royal
battle.
Anyhow,
I will continue,
as I say, serving on
some matters that should be finished up.
We have, at the end of the conclusion of tonight's meeting, we'll have all the data
for our annual report,
which will cover the
fiscal year ending
on June 30.
So, I'll compile that information. I'll forward a Word document
to Agent Wagner
so that it will be available
for the Commission
to review and
ultimately vote on
so that that can be submitted
to the administrative assistant. I will also
work
with the town administrative
assistant to update
the volunteers needed
item that perpetually appears on the town's website. I
will also assist
the new
chair
in accessing
the email account
that has been set up on the town's
email
account with
Microsoft Outlook.
So, there is an IWWC
chair account. You may have seen that address
included in the
send to lists
or copy to lists
on some of the communications that I've sent you.
That email account simply exists as a repository
for messages
from the chair and sometimes to the chair,
so that the stuff that's on my
personal sbcglobal.net
account
doesn't get subpoenaed
by some court.
Not that I expected that would happen, but we all use our private
email accounts for all this business, but it's good to have a public record
of, or a publicly accessible, I should say,
if not to the public, at least to the Commission and to
the town
administration
when it comes to that.
So,
you all will have
some things to look forward to in July,
and
I wish you all the best in finding
additional members
to help carry the load and to,
you know, aid in the deliberations,
make sure we get a balanced viewpoint
on the decisions that the Commission has made.
Any questions or comments?
>> Well, I don't think you should go, George. I think we're going to wrap up this meeting here with the new world's record being done in less than twenty minutes, so we've obviously got
a handle on it now.
>> Well, I appreciate that comment, artificial Larsen. I think that,
yeah, I mightit's
often stated that my only real qualification
for the
business of being chairman was that I
chair a lot of meetings
and like to move things along,
but there's
also got to be room for discussion, deliberation,
and
due consideration
of all the aspects of the work that we're required to do and the regulations that we're required to carry out. This has been a very light year, obviously. I've had a good fortune of not having an awful lot on our plate,
during these meetings. That always expedites things,
you know.
>> Well, thanks for all your work on that, George. And I know you kinda
got moved into the chairman spot unexpectedly,
and
they've you've done a great job over the the time that you've been there. So thank you. Well, thank you, and I appreciate your
>> representing
the Planning and Zoning Commission. You might lean on some of your members to
co participate,
you know, and
feel that obligation of PNZ
to represent itself on IWW.
I
>> did ask who, if there was any interest, and I got no takers, so, Okay,
>> okay.
Yeah, asking for interest is
not often
successful.
We've had some, and I appreciate
those who have stepped
up to
that
invitation.
But again, it's a continual
problem. In a town this size,
we just have
a human resource problem. We have all the commissions to fill and all the offices to fill,
all the boards to fill,
as any other town
and a much smaller population
to draw from
in doing so.
So,
you know, anybody who
wants to be involved in
town affairs
can always find room,
always find a welcoming spot.
Okay,
so that concludes
the business that I had.
Well,
your next regular meeting will be scheduled for July 11,
seven usual time and place.
And
without objection
One objection.
>> Yes. Okay. Well, George, I just wanted to say it's been an honor and a pleasure having you as our chairman.
Learned
a lot about wetlands
and
between you and Jed, that's and Joe, that's where I learned it.
Good. Good. I knew that. That I I did wanna mention too. I can't really mention it to you because you're not gonna be the chairman, but I I was checking my calendar, and I'm not gonna be around next meeting.
I'm
>> gonna be in a in a vehicle or or I'm not gonna be here. So I'm gonna miss the July
meeting.
>> Well, the members present at that time can decide whether they want to defer action
on
conditionon
things that need to be done.
And obviously, it'll
largely depend on, what needs to be done, whether there are any new business to attend to at that time.
>> You You might just find yourself being chairman when you drive that vehicle by. You
>> watch out for those,
what can happen in your absence.
>> Well, if I have to be if that were the case, I would have to, have it at
the little community room, because I am not capable of doing things on a computer, so.
>> Well, fortunately, we don't. I mean, we have
able assistance
with our
board clerk to actually
take care of the tech details.
But yeah, that's one thing that
the Commission can certainly reconsider
and might be actually more appealing. I know that
former Commissioner Megan Lolly,
one of the reasons she dropped off the Commission was that she was just getting computer overload.
Oh, yeah. She's
got a day job that requires
a lot of work,
and, you know, being
at home with children
is not always conducive to having a rational
discussion
on a Zoom call.
So,
the
Commission did very well
determine
that it wanted to go back to having in person meetings,
as was the
>> Well, one of the things that I found by going back to in person planning and zoning meetings
is that if you want to record the meeting
or you want to display anything,
you have to do all the
tricks that George has been doing
anyhow.
So I don't think anybody's meetings are going back to hanging paper
charts on
the wall.
But
it's a steep learning curve, but you could get there. And there is some good
assistance
from the board clerk to
help make that go smoothly.
>> Somebody's out of the anteroom.
Okay.
Well, any other questions or comments
before we
ring off?
Okay,
then again,
without further objection,
declare the meeting adjourned.
And again, thank you for your participation,
and I will
be lurking around for the next twenty five days
to assist and will be available
to assist with transitions
and questions about
moving forward.
Okay, it's been my pleasure, and I say thanks and good night to all. Thanks, George. Good luck to you. Thank you, George. Thanks, George. Thank
you, George.
Good night, everybody. Well and prosper.
Good night.